In the last lecture we detected this error when we change the value of our dropdown, it is related
Bu hatann veya alr listemizin deerini deitirdiimizde alglad son dersi sonlandrn, dorulama
to our validation check in the contact data container. There in check validity,
kontrolmzle ilgili kii veri konteyneri ile ilikili olup onay geerliliini koruyorlar.
we check if rules required,
Kurallarn gerekli olup olmadn kontrol ediyoruz.
the problem is rules,
Sorun kurallardr.
what does this get,
Bu ne alyor.
what does rule of this argument refer to?
Bu argmann kurallar ne anlama gelir?
Let's have a look at where we call check validity,
Geerlilii kontrol etmeye nerde olduumuza bir gz atalm.
we call it in the inputChangedHandler and we pass the update form element value
Buna giri deitirme ileyicisi diyoruz ve gncelleme form eleman deerini iletiyoruz.
and for rules, updatedFormElement validation.
Ve kurallar gncellendi form eleman geerlilii iin.
Now the thing is this validation object doesn't exist for the dropdown for delivery method,
imdi, teslimat yntemi alr kutusu iin bu dorulama nesnesi mevcut deil.
so if we then try to access required on something which doesn't exist, we get an error. Two ways of fixing
Dolaysyla, eriemeyeceimiz bir ey zerinde gerekli olmayan eyleri aratrmaya almazsak, bunu dzeltmek iin iki yol
that,
buluruz.
the first way is simply add an empty validation object to the dropdown control.
Birinci yol, alr kutu denetimine basite bo bir dorulama nesnesi eklemektir.
Now accessing validation required will not fail but simply return undefined,
Gerekli dorulamaya erimek baarsz olmayacak, ancak sadece undefined olarak dnecektir.
I like this way a lot because now all our controls are set up equally,
Bu ekilde holanyorum nk imdi tm kontroller eit ekilde kuruldu.
they all have a validation property and a valid property,
Hepsinin dorulama zellii ve geerlilii olan bir mlk var.
and if they don't need validation, then it should just be empty.
Ve dorulamaya ihtiya duyulmazlarsa, bo olurlar.
This is why I like this approach.
Bu yzden onun yaklamndan holanyordum.
Now the alternative would have been to also add a check in check validity and see if rules,
imdi alternatif de bir kontrol eklemek ve geerlilii kontrol etmek ve kurallar olup olmadn grmek olurdu.
if this is true-ish which it only is if it is defined and if it is not true-ish, so by adding an exclamation
Eer bu doruysaysa, yalnzca onu bulmak ve eer Yahudi deilse o halde neden basite
mark, to simply return true then.
nlem iareti ekleyerek doruyu dndrmektir.
So always return true for the check validity result if no validation rules are defined.
Hibir dorulama kurallar tanmlanmadysa, her kontrol geerlilii sonucunda her zaman dorudur.
We can of course also implement both for double security but again, I like the approach up here by adding
Elbette hem iki gvenlik iin de uygulayabiliriz, ancak yine de bu bo dorulama nesnesini
this empty validation object the most because it makes all the controls configured equally.
en ok ekleyerek yaklam seviyorum nk tm denetimleri eit olarak yaplandryor.
Now with this added, if I save this, now we can change the dropdown value again without getting errors
imdi bu eklendi imdi bu kaydedersem, alma deerini yine de hatasz olarak deitirebiliriz.
as you can see.
Grdn gibi.